Greene Cattle Company collection 1836-1970
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Green Cattle Company collection 1836-1970 (bulk 1900 – 1940)
MS 496
Greene Cattle Company
Greene Cattle Company contains administrative records of various divisions of the Greene Cattle Company Inc. Included in the collection are: legal transactions, financial records,correspondence, photographs, and maps.
56 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
William Cornell Greene was born in Duck Creek, Wisconsin on August 26, 1853 to a Quaker family. The Greene’s had come from New York to the fertile lands of Wisconsin to build a farm. Upon the death of the father Townsend Greene, the family moved back to New York State where William stayed until about 1872 when he headed out West. Little is know about his travels between 1872 and 1877 at which point he reached central Arizona and began prospecting for gold. In 1880, news of rich mineral strikes near Tombstone lured him to southern Arizona, where he would eventually build his mining and cattle empire.
In 1884, Greene married Ella Moson and together they had two daughters, Ella and Eva. Ella also brought with her two children from her previous marriage, Frank and Virginia Moson. They lived together on a ranch in the San Pedro Valley where they raised cattle and farmed various crops. It was during this time that tragedy struck the Greene family. In 1897, his daughter Ella and her friend Katie Corcoran drowned in the river on the San Pedro Ranch. Jim Burnett, a local farmer, was suspected of blowing the river dam on Greene’s property in order to divert more water to his land. The destruction of this dam led to the girls drowning. On July 1, 1897, Burnett had the unfortunate luck of visiting Tombstone at the same time as Greene. Upon seeing Burnett, Greene shot and killed him. Greene was acquitted of any wrongdoing but the incident drew much speculation as he became successful.
Over the next decade Greene was a rancher in the San Pedro Valley but soon his interest returned to prospecting. In 1896 he incorporated the Cananea Copper Company, the first of many mining corporations. After the death of his first wife, Ella Moson Greene in 1899, Greene relocated to Cananea, Sonora, Mexico (although he spent much of his time in New York) and in 1901 he incorporated the Cananea Cattle Company and the Greene Cattle Company. That same year he married the daughter of a long-time acquaintance, Mary Proctor, a woman twenty-five years his junior. The union produced six children, William, Virginia, Frank, Charles, Florence, and Kirk.
At the peak of his career, from 1899-1906, Greene was a man worth almost fifty million dollars. He owned a copper enterprise, a lumber business, and had accumulated almost one million acres of ranch land in both Arizona and Mexico. He gave himself the title of Colonel in order to impress investors back East. By 1908, due to financial woes including the dramatic drop in the price of copper, the events of the Mexican Revolution, and land disputes, Colonel Greene’s mining and lumber empire collapsed. He returned to ranching and managed the Greene Cattle Company and the Cananea Cattle Company until his death on August 5, 1911 resulting from injuries sustained in a carriage accident. For a definitive history of Colonel W.C. Greene, see Colonel Greene and the Copper Skyrocket, by C. L. Sonnichsen.
Colonel Greene’s first venture into ranching occurred in 1882 when he partnered with Ed Roberts, the brother of his first wife Ella, to start a cattle ranch near Tombstone. Between the years of 1884 and 1896, Greene spent his time running the ranch and searching for possible mining claims. Greene’s interest in northern Mexico, particularly Cananea, was sparked in the 1870’s during which time he prospected in the area. After pursuing claims in Cananea for years and without any luck, Greene finally hit pay dirt when he leased four Cananea mines in 1896 including the famous Cobra Grande. He immediately organized his first corporation, the Cananea Copper Company. It was this company and other enterprises that would make Greene a multi-millionaire.
The Greene Cattle Company was incorporated in 1901 encompassing his U.S. land holdings. The Cananea Cattle Company was incorporated the same year for all ranch lands in Mexico. In 1901, the holdings of the Cananea Cattle Company (700,000 acres) vastly outnumbered those of the Greene Cattle Company (100,000 acres). The Greene Cattle Company quickly grew in size. In the first decade of the twentieth century, Greene acquired the San Rafael del Valle Land Grant, the Palominas Ranch, and the San Rafael de la Zanja Land Grant. He raised many cattle on these lands and shipped them to vendors all over the U.S.
In 1910, prior to his untimely death, Greene put his ranch holdings in his wife Mary’s name. Mary, Charles Wiswall - general manager and Mary’s future husband, and the Greene children would run the two cattle companies until they were dissolved. In 1958, the Cananea Cattle Company lands were expropriated by the Mexican government. The Greene Cattle Company was dissolved in 1973 with the sale of the Baca Float.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 5 series
Series I:Legal Series, 1860-1970
Series II:Financial, 1927-1956
Series III:Correspondence, 1930-1963
Series IV:Maps, 1933-1958
Series V:Oversized, 1919-1942
This collection was donated to the Arizona Historical Foundation by Margarethe Greene Lewis from 1974 – 1998. Collection number was formally FM MSS #95. Transferred to the University of Arizona Special Collections in April 2012.
Scope and Content Note
The collection has been arranged and organized by company or individual. The companies include vendors, customers, and the various divisions of the Greene Cattle Company (Green Cattle Company Inc., Greene Cattle Company of Arizona, Greene Cattle Company of California). When the materials apply to general Greene Cattle Company transactions and records, they are organized by type or subject. Each box is then organized alphabetically and chronologically within.
Among the many items of interest within this collection, there are a few that deserve special mention. Of particular importance are the documents pertaining to the Luis Maria Baca Grant. The Baca Grant was awarded to Luis Maria Cabeza de Baca (originally de Vaca) in the mid-sixteenth century by the King of Spain. The grant was made up of five floats or tracts of land totaling almost one million acres. In 1936, the Greene Cattle Company acquired the Luis Maria Baca Grant, Float #5 which is located 50 miles north of Prescott near Seligman, Arizona. The Baca Float as it was called totaled 95,000 acres and would be the last running ranch owned by the Greene Cattle Company until its sale in 1973. Documents pertaining to the Luis Maria Baca Float can be found within every series of this collection. For a short history of the acquisition and operations of the Baca Float, refer to Big Outfit: Ranching on the Baca Float, written by Robert L. Sharp, the general manager of the ranch from 1937 to 1952.
Also deserving mention are the records relating to the J.G. Boswell Company out of California. J.G. Boswell II, the biggest farmer in America and commonly referred to as the ‘King of California.’ The company, started by his uncle J.G. Boswell I in the 1920s, is one of the largest producers of cotton in the United States. During the 1930’s, the J.G. Boswell Company also owned feedlots in California, which were used by the Greene Cattle Company to transport and house their cattle. During the Great Depression, the Greene Cattle Company and the J.G. Boswell Company entered into a joint venture to raise and sell cattle. The continuation of both companies was in part due to the partnership they formed. These records on the J.G. Boswell Company are some of the few records available pertaining to this cotton giant. They can be found in Series I-III of this collection. For a definitive history of J.G. Boswell, refer to The King of California: J.G. Boswell and the Making of a Secret American Empire, by Mark Arax and Rick Wartzman.
Access Terms
Green, William Cornell,1853-1911.
Mineral industries--Arizona.
Cattle--Arizona.
Deeds--Arizona
Land grants--Arizona
San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company.
J.G. Boswell Company
John H. Page and Company
Container List
- Series I: Legal
  Includes land transactions, abstracts of titles, mortgage agreements, meeting minutes, and various other legal documents
  - Abstract of Title Hillman’s 4280 Acres, Tulare County, California, 1860-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abstract of Title Township 17, Yavapai County, Arizona, 1894–1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abstract of Title Township 21, Tulare County, California (1 of 3), 1868–1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abstract of Title Township 21, Tulare County, California (2 of 3), 1868-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abstract of Title Township 21, Tulare County, California (3 of 3), 1868-1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abstracts of Title, Various, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arizona Corporation Commission Reports, 1941-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arizona Livestock Company Abstract of Title, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arizona Livestock Company Mortgage Agreements and Quit-Claim Deed., 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Aztec Land and Cattle Company., 1903-1913 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bank of Bisbee., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bergier, Peter, 1919-1927 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brand Certificates., 1927-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brown, William G., 1916-1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cameron, Colin and Alice F., 1903-1912 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Camou, Juan Pedro M. (aka J.P.M. Camou), 1891–1907 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cananea Cattle Company, 1907-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cananea Realty Company Articles of Incorporation and Meeting Minutes (English and Spanish)(1 of 2), 1910-1925 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cananea Realty Company Articles of Incorporation and Meeting Minutes (English and Spanish)(2 of 2), 1910-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Capital Stock Bills of Sale, 1937–1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chalmers, David G. and Mary A., 1916-1918 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chattel Mortgage Agreements, Various, 1935-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clarke, Harry A., 1922-1927 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - de la Ossa, Osbaldo (Includes Zamora documents), 1911-1919 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Delaney, Bernice and James, 1919-1922 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dodson, D.D. and Ruby, 1903-1922 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Elliott Jr., John H., 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - El Paso and Southwestern Railroad Company, 1911-1913 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Employee Records, 1911-1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - , Fike, Lydia L., 1906-1922 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fourr, Bessie M. and Robert N., 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gibson Abstract Company, 1909-1912 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Greene Cananea Copper Company (Includes an historical sketch), 1941-1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Greene Cattle Company Articles of Incorporation and Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1901-1910 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Greene Cattle Company Articles of Incorporation and Amendments, Appointment of Resident Agent (2 of 2), 1907-1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Greene Cattle Company, Inc. Articles of Incorporation and Amendments, 1937-1950 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Greene Cattle Company, Inc. By-Laws, Meeting Minutes, Waivers, Report to Directors, 1937-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Greene Cattle Company, Inc. vs. County of Yavapai, Arizona, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Greene Cattle Company of Arizona Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Greene Cattle Company of Arizona Board Meeting Minutes, 1926-1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Corporation Commission Reports, 1927-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Greene Cattle Company of California, 1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Greene Cattle Company of California By-Laws and Meeting Minutes, 1927-1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Greene Cattle Company of California Deeds of Land, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Greene, W.C. and Mary P., 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hathaway, James W. and Virginia H., 1918-1923 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Hereford, Frank H. (1 of 4), 1903-1912 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hereford, Frank H. (2 of 4), 1903-1915 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hereford, Frank H. Correspondence Regarding Lieu Land Selection 239 (3 of 4), 1908-1911 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hereford, Frank H. Correspondence Regarding Lieu Land Selection 239 (4 of 4), 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hewitt, Evan, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Holt, William E., 1921-1923 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Inventory of Documents (Possibly used in the office of Greene Cattle Co.), 1905-1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Agreements (1 of 3), 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Agreements (2 of 3), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Agreements (3 of 3), 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Mortgage Agreements, 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Land Parcels Pending Matters, 1909-1914 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Langslow, Eva D. Greene, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Luis Maria Baca Float Abstract of Title (1 of 3), 1915 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Luis Maria Baca Float Abstract of Title (2 of 3), 1928 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Luis Maria Baca Float Abstract of Title (3 of 3), 1931-1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Luis Maria Baca Float Various Documents, 1945-1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Magna Theatre Corporation Rental Agreement, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Martin, Cicero H. and Virginia, 1910-1916 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Sam J., 1921-1925 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Montague, Charles L. (Includes Brown, Calkins, Howe, and Smith documents), 1909-1912 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Page, John H. (Includes Torix family documents), 1912 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Perrin, Edward B., 1903-1937 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Perrin Properties Incorporated, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Phillips, Charles P. and Addie, 1922-1924 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Phillips, Trigg, 1920-1928 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Richardson, Samuel and Mary vs. Della Richardson, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Robe, A.G. Notary Record, 1925-1942 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - , Sailer, Charles X., 1908-1917 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sale and Warranty Deeds, Various, 1891-1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, 1932-1935 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - San Rafael de la Zanja Grant, 1905-1934 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - San Rafael Land and Cattle Company, 1903-1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Santa Cruz County, Arizona Easement for Road Construction (Includes map), 1931 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Co., 1912-1947 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Shattuck, Spencer S., 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Shibley, George S. and Adelle, 1901-1910 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Small, J. Edgar and Linda B., 1926 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Plan, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - State of Arizona Land Leases and Purchases, 1929-1957 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sullivan, John J. and Rhoda, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sun Realty Co. Office Lease for Greene Cattle Company of Ca., 1930-1932 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Territory of New Mexico Documents Baca vs. Salas, Chaves, and Chaves (Includes inventory list of Territory of New Mexico Documents and transcriptions) (1 of 3), 1836-1862 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Territory of New Mexico Documents United States vs. Manuel Barela (Includes transcriptions) (2 of 3), 1862-1863 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Territory of New Mexico Documents Various (Includes transcriptions) (3 of 3), 1847-1892 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior General Land Office, Lease of Lands, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Various, 1909-1952 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Walker, Charles E., 1910-1912 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wiswall, Charles E. and Mary G., 1927-1930 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Yavapai Land and Livestock Improvement Co., 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series II: Financial
  Includes financial statements, stock certificates, cattle sales records, and shipping invoices
  - Bank Statements, Various Ranches, 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bills of Sale, Various, 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Capital Stock Tax Returns, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cattle Sales San Joaquin Valley and Brawley, California, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Chart of Accounts, 1941-1947 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Feedlot Records of Cattle, 1938-1941 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - General Financial, 1945-1960 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Greene Cattle Company of California Stock Certificates, 1927-1937 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (1 of 4), Ja.-Apr. 1934 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (2 of 4), May-Sept. 1934 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (3 of 4), Oct.-Nov. 1934 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (4 of 4), Dec. 1934 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (1 of 2), Ja.-Sept. 1935 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Cattle Sales (2 of 2), Oct.-Dec. 1935 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - J.G Boswell Company Cattle Sales, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - J.G Boswell Company Cattle Sales, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (1 of 4), Ja.-Apr. 1934 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (2 of 4), May-July 1934 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (3 of 4), Aug.-Oct. 1934 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (4 of 4), Nov.-Dec. 1934 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (1 of 2), Jan.-July. 1935 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (2 of 2), Aug.-Dec. 1935 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - J.G. Boswell Company Financial Statements (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Payroll Records (1 of 2), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Payroll Records (2 of 2), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ranchos de Cananea Financial Statements, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Ledger Statements, 1930-1938 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (1 of 2), Ja.-Sept. 1935 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (2 of 2), Oct.-Dec. 1935 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (1 of 3), Jan.-Apr. 1936 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (2 of 3), May-July 1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (3 of 3), Aug.-Dec. 1936 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (1 of 2), Ja.-Apr. 1937 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Shipping Invoices (2 of 2), May-Dec. 1937 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company Shipping Invoices (1 of 3), Jan.-Mar. 1938 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company Shipping Invoices (2 of 3), Apr.-May 1938 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company Shipping Invoices (3 of 3), June-Nov. 1938 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, Weigh Station Receipts, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - San Rafael Land and Cattle Company, 1934-1950 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Seligman, Arizona Ranch Accounts (1 of 3), 1937-1939 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Seligman, Arizona Ranch Accounts (2 of 3), 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Seligman, Arizona Ranch Accounts (3 of 3), 1940 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Stock Certificates Issued, 1937-1941 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Series III: Correspondence
  Primarily consists of correspondence between industry partners, such as the J.G. Boswell Company, and correspondence regarding the patenting of land parcels. Also of note, within this series is a letter dated 1906 from President Theodore Roosevelt to Colonel Greene discussing Greene’s hunting success.
  - General, 1934-1952 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - J.G. Boswell Company, 1930-1932 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (1 of 2), Jan.-June 1933 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (2 of 2), July-Dec. 1933 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (1 of 2), Jan.-July 1934 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (2 of 2), Aug.-Dec 1934 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (1 of 2), Jan..-May 1935 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - J.G. Boswell Company (2 of 2), June-Dec. 1935 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - J.G. Boswell Company, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - J.G. Boswell Company, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - John H. Page and Company, 1946-1952 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - John H. Page and Company, 1953-1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Land Parcels Cochise County, Arizona (1 of 2), 1908-1913 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company Shipping Invoices (2 of 3), 1909-1923 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Land Parcels Hereford, Arizona, 1909-1912 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Land Parcels Moqui Indian Reservation, 1904-1913 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Land Parcels Pinal County, Arizona (1 of 3), 1909-1913 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Land Parcels Pinal County, Arizona (2 of 3), 1909-1913 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Land Parcels Pinal County, Arizona (3 of 3), 1909-1914 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Land Parcels Quotations on Scrip, 1903-1910 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Land Parcels San Rafael de la Zanja Grant, 1908-1913 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Land Parcels San Rafael Ranch (1 of 2), 1909-1921 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Land Parcels San Rafael Ranch (2 of 2), 1909-1946 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Land Parcels Santa Cruz County, Arizona (1 of 3), 1907-1911 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Land Parcels Santa Cruz County, Arizona (2 of 3), 1909-1916 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Land Parcels Santa Cruz County, Arizona (3 of 3), 1908-1916 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Land Parcels Santa Cruz Valley, 1907-1913 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Land Parcels Various Newsclippings, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Luer Packing Company, 1935-1937 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence Roosevelt, Theodore (from), 1906 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1902-1903 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, 1930-1931 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (1 of 2), Jan.-Aug. 1934 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (2 of 2), Sept.-Dec. 1934 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (1 of 2), Jan.-June 1935 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (2 of 2), July-Dec. 1935 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (1 of 2), Jan.-June. 1936 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (2 of 2), July-Dec. 1936 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (1 of 2), Jan.-June 1937 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (2 of 2), July-Dec. 1937 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (1 of 2), Jan.-June 1938 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company (2 of 2), July-Dec. 1938 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - San Rafael Ranch, 1909-1911 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - San Rafael Ranch, 1912-1919 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - San Rafael Ranch, 1920-1921 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - San Rafael Ranch, 1947-1955 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - San Pasqual Land and Cattle Company Shipping Invoices (2 of 3), Apr.-May 1938 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Maps